export const questions =[

    {question:'Who was the first person in space?',answers:['Yuri Gagarin','Tim Peake','Sunita Williams','Helen Sharman'],correctanswer:0},
    {question:'Which planet was the first to be successully visited by an spacecraft?',answers:['Mars','Venus','Jupiter','Mercury'],correctanswer:1},
    {question:'Which of these is not a constellation?',answers:['Crux','Grus','Poloris','Orion'],correctanswer:2},
    {question:'What Planet is closest to the sun?',answers:['Jupiter','Mercury','Earth','Venus'],correctanswer:1},
    {question:'Which of these planest is the smallest',answers:['Jupiter','Earth','Uranus','Mercury'],correctanswer:3},
    {question:'How many moons does Mars have',answers:[2,1,10,3],correctanswer:0},
    {question:'Which planet in the Solar System has the largest ocean?',answers:['Earth','Jupiter','Uranus','Neptune'],correctanswer:1},
    {question:'In what year was Pluto reclassified as a dwarf planet?',answers:[2006,2005,2004,2003],correctanswer:0},
    {question:"Which planet do the moons Operon and Titania belong to?",answers:['Uranus','Venus','Earth','Jupiter'],correctanswer:0},
    {question:'What is the sun mainly made from?',answers:['Rock','Liquid Lava','Gas','Molten iron'],correctanswer:2},
    {question:'How many days does Mercury take to revolve around the Sun?' ,answers:['100 days','88 days','60 days','102 days'],correctanswer:1},
    {question:'Which of the following is not a jovian planet?',answers:['Mars','Jupiter','Saturn','Uranus'],correctanswer:0},
    {question:'Titan is a satellite of',answers:['Mars','Jupiter','Saturn','Earth'],correctanswer:2},
    {question:'Phobos and Deimos are satellites of',answers:['jupiter','Saturn','Venus','Mars'],correctanswer:3},
    {question:'Which planet is also called the red planet?',answers:['Mars','Mercury','Venus','Saturn'],correctanswer:0},
    {question:'Which planet is also called the Morning and Evening star?',answers:['Mars','Earth','Venus','Jupiter'],correctanswer:2},
    {question:'The asteroid belt is located between?',answers:['Earth and Mars','Jupiter and Saturn','Venus and Earth','Mars and Jupiter'],correctanswer:3},
    {question:'The shape of Milky way galaxy is ?',answers:['Round','Elleptical','Oval','Rectangular'],correctanswer:1},
    {question:'The largest satellite of our solar system is ?',answers:['Deimos','Gyanemide','Titan','Phobos'],correctanswer:2},
    {question:'The two planets that revolve anti-clockwise around the sun are?',answers:['Venus and Uranus','Mars and Jupiter','Saturn and Mercury','Earth and Mars'],correctanswer:0},
    {question:'Our Solar System is 4.6 billion years old, but how old is the Earth?',answers:['560 million years','1.3 billion years','2.6 billion years','4.5 billion years'],correctanswer:3},
    {question:'Which country was the first to travel in space?',answers:['USA','Soviet Union','China','United Kingdom'],correctanswer:1},
    {question:'Saturn is the planet with the most moons in the Solar System. How many moons does it have?',answers:[82,85,72,10],correctanswer:0},
    {question:'When was the first extrasolar planet discovered',answers:['1995','1990','1992','1999'],correctanswer:2},
    {question:'Which planet in the Solar System is furthest from the Sun?',answers:['Neptune','Uranus','Mercury','Jupiter'],correctanswer:0}
  
]
  questions.sort((a, b) => 0.5 - Math.random());
  questions.length=20


